Hello

I'm Oliver John Cruz

#7 Abra Street Barretto Olongapo City Philippines +639302229266 cruzoliverjohn@gmail.com 25 years old - Sep/25/1996 Male | Single | Filipino



Skills

I'm a **designer** & **front end developer** based in the Philippines, specializing in designing exceptional websites, applications, and everything in between. Currently designing websites and marketing materials for DBA Global Shared Services Inc. My 4+ years of experience in the field helped me grow a love for timeless, clean and minimal design. I always keep an eye for clean, nice visual design for websites and applications.

- Logo Design & Branding
- Social Media Marketing
- Flyers, Posters, Brochures etc.
- Web and Mobile UI/UX

- Page Layout (Books, Magazines)
- Front-End Developer (Wordpress, HTML+CSS)

Tools

- Figma
- XD
- Zeplin
- Miro

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign
- DreamWeaver
- HTML+CSS
- Wordpress
- Notion
- Microsoft Office

Experience

November 2021 - PRESENT

DBA Advisory, SBMA PH - Associate Web Developer/Graphic Designer

- Design and develop concepts for branding, marketing, and communication materials, e.g., web pages, brochures, logos, signs, books, magazine covers, annual reports, advertisements, etc.
- Create branding, marketing and communication materials using software, e.g., Adobe's Creative Suite—including Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, etc.
- Create style guides for how logos and other branding collateral should be displayed and used.
- Meet with Clients to receive design briefs and gain an understanding of their requirements.

- Create or incorporate illustrations, pictures, and designs to reflect the Clients' brand, desired theme, and tone.
- Conceptualize the appropriate colors, font and font size, images, and other visuals to enhance the readability of text and image.
- Work with copywriters and other creative team members to produce content.
- Prepare and produce mock-ups based on Client requirements for review and make changes or revisions after receiving feedback.
- Review final mock-up and suggest improvements, if required.
- Ensure final graphics and mock-ups are visually appealing and on-brand.
- Test graphics across various media Designing visual arts for functions and company events. Designing and printing of marketing collateral for the company such as flyers, brochures, newsletter etc.
- Other ad hoc tasks that may be assigned.

May 2019 - November 2021

EasyPos Solutions (Deliverit Software), SBMA PH - UI/UX Designer

- Creating design proposals for mobile apps and websites to promote ideas and concepts to stakeholders.
- Working effectively as part of the design team to provide rapid support and feedback on tasks involving UI design, UX journey analysis and configuration to ensure a consistent approach to the customer journeys.
- Translate complex interactions into simple, engaging solutions and be able to communicate those solutions verbally as well as through sketches, user flows, wireframes, hi-fl mocks and functional prototypes.
- Working hand in hand with internal teams(Product Designer, Product Owners & Developers) to progressively move from low fidelity to high fidelity designs.

September 2018 - May 2019

EasyPos Solutions (Deliverit Software), SBMA PH - Front-End Developer

- Implementing responsible web design principles to ensure that the website renders well across multiple devices.
- Monitoring and improving website performance and traffic related to site usability problems.
- Design and maintain websites using the appropriate coding and scripting languages, content management tools, and other related software applications.
- Write, design, edit webpage content, perform website updates as needed and write code for websites or web applications.
- Design branding and logo based on client request.

June 2018 - September 2018

EasyPos Solutions (Deliverit Software), SBMA PH - Technical Support Engineer

- Monitoring and maintaining the product and service offered by the company and to troubleshoot Hardware and Software issues on the phone.
- Ensuring that the products meet certain thresholds of acceptability.
- To test, direct or coordinate quality assurance programs and formulate quality control policies.

June 2017 - June 2018

RAS Contact Solutions, SBMA PH - Customer Service Representative

 Managing incoming calls and customer service inquiries, Identifying and assessing customers' needs to achieve satisfaction, generating sales leads that develop into new customers.

Education

Bachelor's Degree - 2017

Lyceum of Subic Bay, SBMA PH - Information Technology

Awards

Interaction Design Foundation - 2021

<u>User Experience: The Beginner's Guide</u>

Udemy - 2019

The Complete SEO Training Masterclass 2020

Lyceum of Subic Bay - 2016

Best System Analysis and Design Project

TESDA - 2015

National Certificate in Visual Graphics Design II

Microsoft - 2014

Microsoft Office Specialist for Office Word & Access 2010

Reference

- Edmon Balingit Senior Web Developer, DBA Advisory
 - edmon.balingit@dbaadvisory.com
- Jake Nuñez Lead UI/UX Designer, EasyPos Solutions
 - jakealfrednunez@gmail.com